<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Case Studies | ABZ</title><link>/case-studies/</link><atom:link href="/case-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Case Studies</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2024 ABZ Conference</copyright><image><url>/img/https:/github.com/abz-conf/abz-conf.logo/raw/master/obj/rect/256.png</url><title>Case Studies</title><link>/case-studies/</link></image><item><title>Mechanical Lung Ventilator (ABZ 2024)</title><link>/case-study/abz24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/case-study/abz24/</guid><description>&lt;p>This document presents the case study for ABZ 2024 conference. The case study introduces Mechanical Lung Ventilator (MLV). The MLV is intended to provide ventilation support for patients that require mechanical ventilation in two operative modes: Pressure Controlled Ventilation (PCV) and Pressure Support Ventilation (PSV). The former is used when patients are not able to start breathing on their own, while the latter support patients by partially taking over the work of breathing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a more detailed description of the case study, and the document reporting the requirements see
&lt;a href="../../site/2024/casestudy">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AMAN Case Study (ABZ 2023)</title><link>/case-study/abz23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/case-study/abz23/</guid><description>&lt;p>This document presents the case study for ABZ 2023 conference. The case study introduces a safety critical interactive system called
AMAN (Arrival MANager) which is a partly-autonomous scheduler of landing sequences of aircraft in airports. This interactive systems interleaves Air Traffic Controllers activities with automation in AMAN. While some AMAN systems are currently deployed in airports, we consider here only a subset of functions which represent a challenge in modelling and verification.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adaptive Exterior Light and Speed Control System (ABZ 2020)</title><link>/case-study/abz20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/case-study/abz20/</guid><description>&lt;p>This document describes two systems from the automotive domain: an adaptive exterior light system (ELS) and a speed control system (SCS). This specification is based on the SPES XT running example. Besides their general architectures, the requirements of the software based controllers are described. Both systems are only loosely coupled, which makes it possible to handle them independently&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hybrid ERTMS/ETCS Level 3 (ABZ 2018)</title><link>/case-study/abz18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/case-study/abz18/</guid><description>&lt;p>This document presents a description of the European Rail Traffic Management System (ERTMS) case study. ERTMS is a system of standards for management and interoperation of signalling for railways by the European Union (EU). The case study focuses on the ERTMS Level 3 Hybrid principle, which accommodates different types of trains including ERTMS trains equiped with the Train Integrity Monitoring System (TIMS), ERTMS trains without TIMS, and non-ERTMS trains.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hemodialysis Machine (ABZ 2016)</title><link>/case-study/abz16/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/case-study/abz16/</guid><description>&lt;p>This documents presents a description of a case study concerning the control of a hemodialysis (HD) machine.
It provides an overview of the requirements and the design of an HD machine including a sketch of the machine’s functionality, related safety conditions, and a top-level system architectural description.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Landing Gear System (ABZ 2014)</title><link>/case-study/abz14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/case-study/abz14/</guid><description>&lt;p>This document presents a landing gear system. It describes the system and provides some of its requirements. We propose this case study as a benchmark for techniques and tools dedicated to the verification of behavioral properties of systems.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>