<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Issam Maamria | ABZ</title><link>/author/issam-maamria/</link><atom:link href="/author/issam-maamria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Issam Maamria</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2025 ABZ Conference</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/img/https:/github.com/abz-conf/abz-conf.logo/raw/master/obj/rect/256.png</url><title>Issam Maamria</title><link>/author/issam-maamria/</link></image><item><title>Event-B Code Generation: Type Extension with Theories</title><link>/publication/edmundsbmsl12/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/edmundsbmsl12/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Event-B method is a formal modelling approach; our interest is the final step, of generating code for concurrent programs, from Event-B. Our Tasking Event-B tool integrates Event-B to facilitate code generation. The theory plug-in allows mathematical extensions to be added to an Event-B development. When working at the implementation level we need to consider how to translate the newly added types and operators into code. In this paper, we augment the theory plug-in, by adding a Translation Rules section to the tool. This enables us to define translation rules that map Event-B formulas to code. We illustrate the approach using a small case study, where we add a theory of arrays, and specify translation rules for generating Ada code.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you cannot see the document below, the PDF document is most likely not freely accessible. In this case, please try to access the document via this &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007%2F978-3-642-30885-7_33.pdf">link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-642-30885-7_33.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{EdmundsBMSL12,
author = {Andrew Edmunds and
Michael J. Butler and
Issam Maamria and
Renato Silva and
Chris Lovell},
editor = {John Derrick and
John S. Fitzgerald and
Stefania Gnesi and
Sarfraz Khurshid and
Michael Leuschel and
Steve Reeves and
Elvinia Riccobene},
title = {Event-B Code Generation: Type Extension with Theories},
booktitle = {Abstract State Machines, Alloy, B, VDM, and {Z} - Third International
Conference, {ABZ} 2012, Pisa, Italy, June 18-21, 2012. Proceedings},
series = {Lecture Notes in Computer Science},
volume = {7316},
pages = {365--368},
publisher = {Springer},
year = {2012},
url = {https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-30885-7\_33},
doi = {10.1007/978-3-642-30885-7\_33},
timestamp = {Sun, 02 Jun 2019 21:23:59 +0200},
biburl = {https://dblp.org/rec/conf/asm/EdmundsBMSL12.bib},
bibsource = {dblp computer science bibliography, https://dblp.org}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;!-- # add information for case study papers (if available)
## Sources
- **Used formal method:**
[ASM](/method/asm)
- **Resources and tools:**
Asmeta
For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:silvia.bonfanti@unibg.it;arcaini@nii.ac.jp;angelo.gargantini@unibg.it;scandurra@unibg.it;elvinia.riccobene@unimi.it">authors&lt;/a>--></description></item><item><title>On an Extensible Rule-Based Prover for Event-B</title><link>/publication/maamriaber10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/maamriaber10/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Event-B [1] is a formalism for discrete system modelling. The Rodin platform [2] provides a toolset to carry out specification, refinement and proof in Event-B. The importance of proofs as part of formal modelling cannot be emphasised enough, and as such, it is imperative to provide effective tool support for it. An important aspect of this support is the extensibility of the prover, and more pressingly, how its soundness is preserved while allowing extensibility. Rodin has a limited support for adding rules as this requires (a) a deep understanding of the internal architecture and (b) knowledge of the Java language. Our approach attempts to provide support for user-defined proof rules. We initially focus on supporting rewrite rules to enhance the rewriting capabilities of Rodin. To achieve this objective, we introduce a theory construct distinct from contexts and machines. The theory construct provides a platform for the users to define rewrite rules both conditional and unconditional. As part of rule definition, users decide whether the rule is to be applied automatically or interactively. Each defined rule gives rise to proof obligations that serve to verify its conservativity. In this respect, it is required that validity and well-definedness are preserved by rules. After the conservativity of all rules contained in a theory is established, the theory can then be deployed and available to the proving activity. In order to apply rewrite rules, it is necessary to single out applicable rules to any given sequent. This is achieved through a pattern matching mechanism which is implemented as an extension to Rodin. Our approach has two advantages. Firstly, it offers a uniform mechanism to add proof rule without the need to write Java code. Secondly, it provides a means to verify added rules using proof obligations. Our work is still in progress, and research has to be carried out to (a) cover a larger set of rewrite and inference rules, and (b) provide guidelines to help the theory developer with deciding whether a given rule should be applied automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you cannot see the document below, the PDF document is most likely not freely accessible. In this case, please try to access the document via this &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007%2F978-3-642-11811-1_40.pdf">link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-642-11811-1_40.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{MaamriaBER10,
author = {Issam Maamria and
Michael J. Butler and
Andrew Edmunds and
Abdolbaghi Rezazadeh},
editor = {Marc Frappier and
Uwe Gl{\&amp;quot;{a}}sser and
Sarfraz Khurshid and
R{\'{e}}gine Laleau and
Steve Reeves},
title = {On an Extensible Rule-Based Prover for Event-B},
booktitle = {Abstract State Machines, Alloy, {B} and Z, Second International Conference,
{ABZ} 2010, Orford, QC, Canada, February 22-25, 2010. Proceedings},
series = {Lecture Notes in Computer Science},
volume = {5977},
pages = {407},
publisher = {Springer},
year = {2010},
url = {https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-11811-1\_40},
doi = {10.1007/978-3-642-11811-1\_40},
timestamp = {Tue, 14 May 2019 10:00:50 +0200},
biburl = {https://dblp.org/rec/conf/asm/MaamriaBER10.bib},
bibsource = {dblp computer science bibliography, https://dblp.org}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;!-- # add information for case study papers (if available)
## Sources
- **Used formal method:**
[ASM](/method/asm)
- **Resources and tools:**
Asmeta
For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:silvia.bonfanti@unibg.it;arcaini@nii.ac.jp;angelo.gargantini@unibg.it;scandurra@unibg.it;elvinia.riccobene@unimi.it">authors&lt;/a>--></description></item></channel></rss>