<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nazareno Aguirre | ABZ</title><link>/author/nazareno-aguirre/</link><atom:link href="/author/nazareno-aguirre/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Nazareno Aguirre</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2025 ABZ Conference</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/img/https:/github.com/abz-conf/abz-conf.logo/raw/master/obj/rect/256.png</url><title>Nazareno Aguirre</title><link>/author/nazareno-aguirre/</link></image><item><title>An Analysis of the Impact of Field-Value Instance Navigation in Alloy&amp;apos;s Model Finding</title><link>/publication/cornejonpafbr24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/cornejonpafbr24/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The use of SAT-based model finding for specification analysis is a crucial characteristic of Alloy, and a main reason of its success as a language for software specification. When a property of a specification is analyzed and deemed satisfiable, the user usually explores instances of the corresponding satisfiability, in order to understand the analysis outcome. The order in which instances are obtained during exploration can impact the efficiency and effectiveness with which specification analysis is carried out. This has been observed by various researchers, and different instance exploration strategies have been proposed, besides the standard SAT-solver driven strategy implemented with the Alloy Analyzer. In this paper, we concentrate on a strategy recently proposed in the literature, that we refer to as “field-value” driven, and has been implemented in the tool HawkEye. The tool allows the user to interactively guide instance exploration, by enforcing constraints requiring fields to contain (resp., do not contain) specific values. We design an experiment involving faulty Alloy specifications featuring combinations of over constraints and under constraints, and perform a user study to analyze the impact of this instance exploration strategy, in comparison with the standard SAT-solver driven exploration. The study focuses on HawkEye’s facility of interactive instance querying and how it may favor users, in its current realization, during Alloy model analysis and debugging. We perform an assessment of the evaluation, and summarize some of the reasons that may diminish the impact of field-value exploration in model finding.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you cannot see the document below, the PDF document is most likely not freely accessible. In this case, please try to access the document via this &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007%2F978-3-031-63790-2_9.pdf">link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-031-63790-2_9.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{CornejoNPAFBR24,
author = {C{\'{e}}sar Cornejo and
Mar{\'{\i}}a Marta Novaira and
Sonia Permigiani and
Nazareno Aguirre and
Marcelo F. Frias and
Sim{\'{o}}n Guti{\'{e}}rrez Brida and
Germ{\'{a}}n Regis},
editor = {Silvia Bonfanti and
Angelo Gargantini and
Michael Leuschel and
Elvinia Riccobene and
Patrizia Scandurra},
title = {An Analysis of the Impact of Field-Value Instance Navigation in Alloy's
Model Finding},
booktitle = {Rigorous State-Based Methods - 10th International Conference, {ABZ}
2024, Bergamo, Italy, June 25-28, 2024, Proceedings},
series = {Lecture Notes in Computer Science},
volume = {14759},
pages = {141--159},
publisher = {Springer},
year = {2024},
url = {https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-63790-2\_9},
doi = {10.1007/978-3-031-63790-2\_9},
timestamp = {Mon, 03 Mar 2025 21:25:08 +0100},
biburl = {https://dblp.org/rec/conf/zum/CornejoNPAFBR24.bib},
bibsource = {dblp computer science bibliography, https://dblp.org}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;!-- # add information for case study papers (if available)
## Sources
- **Used formal method:**
[ASM](/method/asm)
- **Resources and tools:**
Asmeta
For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:silvia.bonfanti@unibg.it;arcaini@nii.ac.jp;angelo.gargantini@unibg.it;scandurra@unibg.it;elvinia.riccobene@unimi.it">authors&lt;/a>--></description></item></channel></rss>