<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jiachen Chen | ABZ</title><link>/author/jiachen-chen/</link><atom:link href="/author/jiachen-chen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Jiachen Chen</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2026 ABZ Conference</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/img/https:/github.com/abz-conf/abz-conf.logo/raw/master/obj/rect/256.png</url><title>Jiachen Chen</title><link>/author/jiachen-chen/</link></image><item><title>Formal Verification of Interoperability Between Future Network Architectures Using Alloy</title><link>/publication/jahaniancr20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/jahaniancr20/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Internet is composed of many interconnected, interoperating networks. With the recent advances in Future Internet design, multiple new network architectures, especially Information-Centric Networks (ICN) have emerged. Given the ubiquity of networks based on the Internet Protocol (IP), it is likely that we will have a number of different interconnecting network domains with different architectures, including ICNs. Their interoperability is important, but at the same time difficult to prove. A formal tool can be helpful for such analysis. ICNs have a number of unique characteristics, warranting formal analysis, establishing properties that go beyond, and are different from, what have been used in the state-of-the-art because ICN operates at the level of content names rather than node addresses. We need to focus on node-to-content reachability, rather than node-to-node reachability. In this paper, we present a formal approach to model and analyze information-centric interoperability (ICI). We use Alloy Analyzer’s model finding approach to verify properties expressed as invariants for information-centric services (both pull and push-based models) including content reachability and returnability. We extend our use of Alloy to model counting, to quantitatively analyze failure and mobility properties. We present a formally-verified ICI framework that allows for seamless interoperation among a multitude of network architectures. We also report on the impact of domain types, routing policies, and binding techniques on the probability of content reachability and returnability, under failures and mobility.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you cannot see the document below, the PDF document is most likely not freely accessible. In this case, please try to access the document via this &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007%2F978-3-030-48077-6_4.pdf">link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-030-48077-6_4.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{JahanianCR20,
author = {Mohammad Jahanian and
Jiachen Chen and
K. K. Ramakrishnan},
editor = {Alexander Raschke and
Dominique M{\'{e}}ry and
Frank Houdek},
title = {Formal Verification of Interoperability Between Future Network Architectures
Using Alloy},
booktitle = {Rigorous State-Based Methods - 7th International Conference, {ABZ}
2020, Ulm, Germany, May 27-29, 2020, Proceedings},
series = {Lecture Notes in Computer Science},
volume = {12071},
pages = {44--60},
publisher = {Springer},
year = {2020},
url = {https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-48077-6\_4},
doi = {10.1007/978-3-030-48077-6\_4},
timestamp = {Mon, 25 May 2020 12:33:39 +0200},
biburl = {https://dblp.org/rec/conf/asm/JahanianCR20.bib},
bibsource = {dblp computer science bibliography, https://dblp.org}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;!-- # add information for case study papers (if available)
## Sources
- **Used formal method:**
[ASM](/method/asm)
- **Resources and tools:**
Asmeta
For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:silvia.bonfanti@unibg.it;arcaini@nii.ac.jp;angelo.gargantini@unibg.it;scandurra@unibg.it;elvinia.riccobene@unimi.it">authors&lt;/a>--></description></item></channel></rss>