<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nadera Slimani | ABZ</title><link>/author/nadera-slimani/</link><atom:link href="/author/nadera-slimani/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Nadera Slimani</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2025 ABZ Conference</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/img/https:/github.com/abz-conf/abz-conf.logo/raw/master/obj/rect/256.png</url><title>Nadera Slimani</title><link>/author/nadera-slimani/</link></image><item><title>Secrecy UML Method for Model Transformations</title><link>/publication/hassansal10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/hassansal10/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This paper introduces the subject of secrecy models development by transformation, with formal validation. In an enterprise, constructing a secrecy model is a participatory exercise involving policy makers and implementers. Policy makers iteratively provide business governance requirements, while policy implementers formulate rules of access in computer-executable terms. The process is error prone and may lead to undesirable situations thus threatening the security of the enterprise. At each iteration, a security officer (SO) needs to guarantee business continuity by ensuring property preservation; as well, he needs to check for potential threats due to policy changes. This paper proposes a method that is meant to address both aspects: the formal analysis of transformation results and the formal proof that transformations are property preserving. UML is used for expressing and transforming models [1], and the Alloy analyzer is used to perform integrity checks [3]. Governance requirements dictate a security policy, that regulates access to information. This policy is implemented by means of secrecy models. Hence, the SO defines the mandatory secrecy rules as a part of enterprise governance model in order to implement security policy. For instance, a secrecy rule may state: higher-ranking officers have read rights to information at lower ranks. Automation helps reduce design errors of combined and complex secrecy models [2]. However, current industry practices do not include precise methods for constructing and validating enterprise governance models. Our research proposes a formal transformation method to construct secrecy models by way of applying transformations to a base UML model (BM). For example, starting from the BM, with only three primitives: Subject/Verb/Object, we can generate RBAC0 in addition to SecureUML [2] model. By way of examples and by means of formal analysis we intend to show that, using our method, a SO is able to build different types of secrecy models and validate them for consistency, in addition to detecting scenarios resulting from unpreserved properties.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you cannot see the document below, the PDF document is most likely not freely accessible. In this case, please try to access the document via this &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007%2F978-3-642-11811-1_35.pdf">link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-642-11811-1_35.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{HassanSAL10,
author = {Wa{\&amp;quot;{e}}l Hassan and
Nadera Slimani and
Kamel Adi and
Luigi Logrippo},
editor = {Marc Frappier and
Uwe Gl{\&amp;quot;{a}}sser and
Sarfraz Khurshid and
R{\'{e}}gine Laleau and
Steve Reeves},
title = {Secrecy {UML} Method for Model Transformations},
booktitle = {Abstract State Machines, Alloy, {B} and Z, Second International Conference,
{ABZ} 2010, Orford, QC, Canada, February 22-25, 2010. Proceedings},
series = {Lecture Notes in Computer Science},
volume = {5977},
pages = {400},
publisher = {Springer},
year = {2010},
url = {https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-11811-1\_35},
doi = {10.1007/978-3-642-11811-1\_35},
timestamp = {Sat, 31 May 2025 23:08:41 +0200},
biburl = {https://dblp.org/rec/conf/asm/HassanSAL10.bib},
bibsource = {dblp computer science bibliography, https://dblp.org}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;!-- # add information for case study papers (if available)
## Sources
- **Used formal method:**
[ASM](/method/asm)
- **Resources and tools:**
Asmeta
For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:silvia.bonfanti@unibg.it;arcaini@nii.ac.jp;angelo.gargantini@unibg.it;scandurra@unibg.it;elvinia.riccobene@unimi.it">authors&lt;/a>--></description></item></channel></rss>