<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ABZ'20 | ABZ</title><link>/tag/abz20/</link><atom:link href="/tag/abz20/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>ABZ'20</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023 ABZ Conference</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/img/https:/github.com/abz-conf/abz-conf.logo/raw/master/obj/rect/256.png</url><title>ABZ'20</title><link>/tag/abz20/</link></image><item><title>ABZ 2020 (Ulm, Germany)</title><link>/2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>This conference was postponed due to the international outbreak of CoVid-19. See
&lt;a href="/2021/">ABZ 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Verified Low-Level Implementation of the Adaptive Exterior Light and Speed Control System</title><link>/publication/krings2020abz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/krings2020abz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this article, we present an approach to the ABZ 2020 case study, that differs from the ones usually presented at ABZ: Rather than using a (correct-by-construction) approach following a formal method, we use MISRA C for a low-level implementation instead. We strictly adhere to test-driven development for validation, and only afterwards apply model checking using CBMC for verification. In consequence, our realization of the ABZ case study can serve as a baseline reference for comparison, allowing to assess the benefit provided by the various formal modeling languages, methods and tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-030-48077-6_30.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{krings2020abz,
title={{A Verified Low-Level Implementation of the Adaptive Exterior Light and Speed Control System}},
author={Krings, Sebastian and Koerner, Philipp and Dunkelau, Jannik and Rutenkolk, Chris},
booktitle={7th International Conference on Rigorous State Based Methods (ABZ'20)},
pages={382--397},
year={2020},
organization={Springer}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
MISRA C&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:sebastian@krin.gs;p.koerner@hhu.de;jannik.dunkelau@hhu.de;chris.rutenkolk@hhu.de">authors&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>An Event-B Model of an Automotive Adaptive Exterior Light System</title><link>/publication/mammar2020abz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/mammar2020abz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This paper introduces an Event-B formal model of the adaptive exterior light system for cars, a case study proposed in the context of the ABZ2020 conference. The system describes the different provided lights and the conditions under which they are switched on/off in order to improve the visibility of the driver without dazzling the oncoming ones. The system can be viewed as a lights controller that reads different information form the available sensors (key state, exterior luminosity, etc.) and takes the adequate actions by acting on the actuators of the lights in order to ensure a good visibility for the driver according to the information read. Our model is built using stepwise refinement with the Event-B method. We consider all the features of the case study, all proof obligations have been discharged using the rodin provers. Our model has been validated using ProB by applying the different provided scenarios. This validation has permitted us to point out and correct some mistakes, ambiguities and oversights in the first versions of the case study.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-030-48077-6_28.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{mammar2020abz,
title={{An Event-B Model of an Automotive Adaptive Exterior Light System}},
author={Mammar, Amel and Frappier, Marc and Laleau, Regine},
booktitle={7th International Conference on Rigorous State Based Methods (ABZ'20)},
pages={351--366},
year={2020},
organization={Springer}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/method/event-b">Event-B&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:amel.mammar@telecom-sudparis.eu;marc.frappier@usherbrooke.ca;laleau@u-pec.fr">authors&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Modeling of a Speed Control System using Event-B</title><link>/publication/mammar2020abz_/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/mammar2020abz_/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The present paper presents our proposal of an Event-B model of a speed control system, a part of the case study provided in the ABZ2020 conference. The case study describes how the system regulates the current speed of a car according to a set criteria like the speed desired by the driver, the position of a possible preceding vehicle but also a given speed limit that the driver must not exceed. For that purpose, this controller reads different information form the available sensors (key state, desired speed, etc.) and takes the adequate actions by acting on the actuators of the car&amp;rsquo;s speed according to the read information. To formally model this system, we adopt a stepwise refinement approach with the Event-B method. We consider most features of the case study, all proof obligations have been discharged using the Rodin provers. Our model has been validated using ProB by applying the different provided scenarios. This validation has permitted us to point out and correct some mistakes, ambiguities and oversights contained in the first versions of the case study.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-030-48077-6_29.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{mammar2020modeling,
title={{Modeling of a Speed Control System using Event-B}},
author={Mammar, Amel and Frappier, Marc},
booktitle={7th International Conference on Rigorous State Based Methods (ABZ'20)},
pages={367--381},
year={2020},
organization={Springer}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/method/event-b">Event-B&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:amel.mammar@telecom-sudparis.eu;marc.frappier@usherbrooke.ca">authors&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Modelling an automotive software-intensive system with adaptive features using ASMETA</title><link>/publication/arcaini2020abz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/arcaini2020abz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the context of automotive domain, modern control systems are software-intensive and have adaptive features to provide safety and comfort. These software-based features demand software engineering approaches and formal methods that are able to guarantee correct operation, since malfunctions may cause harm/damage. Adaptive Exterior Light and the Speed Control Systems are examples of software-intensive systems that equip modern cars. We have used the Abstract State Machines to model the behaviour of both control systems. Each model has been developed through model refinement, following the incremental way in which functional requirements are given. We used the asmeta tool-set to support the simulation of the abstract models, their validation against the informal requirements, and the verification of behavioural properties. In this paper, we discuss our modelling, validation and verification strategies, and the results (in terms of features addressed and not) of our activities. In particular, we provide insights on how we addressed the adaptive features (the adaptive high beam headlights and the adaptive cruise control) by explicitly modelling their software control loops according to the MAPE-K (Monitor-Analyse-Plan-Execute over a shared Knowledge) reference control model for self-adaptive systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-030-48077-6_25.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{arcaini2020abz,
title={{Modelling an automotive software-intensive system with adaptive features using ASMETA}},
author={Arcaini, Paolo and Bonfanti, Silvia and Gargantini, Angelo and Riccobene, Elvinia and Scandurra, Patrizia},
booktitle={7th International Conference on Rigorous State Based Methods (ABZ'20)},
pages={302--317},
year={2020},
organization={Springer}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/method/asm">ASM&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Resources and tools:&lt;/strong>
Asmeta&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:silvia.bonfanti@unibg.it;arcaini@nii.ac.jp;angelo.gargantini@unibg.it;scandurra@unibg.it;elvinia.riccobene@unimi.it">authors&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Modelling and Validating an Automotive System in Classical B and Event-B</title><link>/publication/leuschel2020abz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/leuschel2020abz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We have modelled parts of the ABZ automotive case study using the B-method. For the early phases of modelling we have used the classical B for software, while for proof we have used Event-B and Rodin. It is maybe surprising that classical B&amp;rsquo;s machine inclusion mechanism along with operation calls can be used for modular system modelling. Moreover, for one particular style of modelling, the result can then be translated to superposition refinement with event extension in Event-B. Before conducting the proof, we have validated our models using model checking and animation with visualizations. The graphical visualizations were constructed using a new plugin (VisB) which helped uncover errors and transforms our model into an executable, interactive reference specification which can be examined by users without formal background.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-030-48077-6_27.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{leuschel2020abz,
title={{Modelling and Validating an Automotive System in Classical B and Event-B}},
author={Leuschel, Michael and Mutz, Mareike and Werth, Michelle},
booktitle={7th International Conference on Rigorous State Based Methods (ABZ'20)},
pages={335--350},
year={2020},
organization={Springer}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/method/b">Classical B&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="/method/event-b">Event-B&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Resources and tools:&lt;/strong>
VisB&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:michael.leuschel@hhu.de">authors&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Validating Multiple Variants of an Automotive Light System with Electrum</title><link>/publication/cunha2020abz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/cunha2020abz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This paper reports on the development and validation of a formal model for an automotive adaptive exterior lights system (ELS) with multiple variants in Electrum, a lightweight formal specification language that extends Alloy with mutable relations and temporal logic. We explore different strategies to address variability, one in pure Electrum and another through an annotative language extension. We then show how Electrum and its Analyzer can be used to validate systems of this nature, namely by checking that the reference scenarios are admissible, and to automatically verify whether the established requirements hold. A prototype was developed to translate the provided validation sequences into Electrum and back to further automate the validation process. The resulting ELS model was validated against the provided validation sequences and verified for most of requirements for all variants.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-030-48077-6_26.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{cunha22020abz,
title={{Validating Multiple Variants of an Automotive Light System with Electrum}},
author={Cunha, Alcino and Macedo, Nuno and Liu, Chong},
booktitle={7th International Conference on Rigorous State Based Methods (ABZ'20)},
pages={318--334},
year={2020},
organization={Springer}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
Electrum&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Resources and tools:&lt;/strong>
Electrum&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:nfmmacedo@di.uminho.pt">authors&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Adaptive Exterior Light and Speed Control System</title><link>/publication/houdek2018abz-cs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/houdek2018abz-cs/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This case study continues the successful series of case studies for formal specification and verification of the ABZ conference series, which started with the landing gear system and expanded with the hemodialysis medical device and the European Train Control System (ETCS) in the following years. This document describes two systems from the automotive domain: an adaptive exterior light system (ELS) and a speed control system (SCS). This specification is based on the SPES XT running example. Besides their general architectures, the requirements of the software based controllers are described. Both systems are only loosely coupled, which makes it possible to handle them independently&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/abz2020.uni-ulm.de\/resources\/files\/casestudyABZ2020v1.17.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{houdek2020adaptive,
title={Adaptive exterior light and speed control system},
author={Houdek, Frank and Raschke, Alexander},
booktitle={International Conference on Rigorous State-Based Methods},
pages={281--301},
year={2020},
organization={Springer}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Adaptive Exterior Light and Speed Control System (ABZ 2020)</title><link>/case-study/abz20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/case-study/abz20/</guid><description>&lt;p>This document describes two systems from the automotive domain: an adaptive exterior light system (ELS) and a speed control system (SCS). This specification is based on the SPES XT running example. Besides their general architectures, the requirements of the software based controllers are described. Both systems are only loosely coupled, which makes it possible to handle them independently&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>