<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Régine Laleau | ABZ</title><link>/author/regine-laleau/</link><atom:link href="/author/regine-laleau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Régine Laleau</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2025 ABZ Conference</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/img/https:/github.com/abz-conf/abz-conf.logo/raw/master/obj/rect/256.png</url><title>Régine Laleau</title><link>/author/regine-laleau/</link></image><item><title>An Event-B Model of an Automotive Adaptive Exterior Light System</title><link>/publication/mammar2020abz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/mammar2020abz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This paper introduces an Event-B formal model of the adaptive exterior light system for cars, a case study proposed in the context of the ABZ2020 conference. The system describes the different provided lights and the conditions under which they are switched on/off in order to improve the visibility of the driver without dazzling the oncoming ones. The system can be viewed as a lights controller that reads different information form the available sensors (key state, exterior luminosity, etc.) and takes the adequate actions by acting on the actuators of the lights in order to ensure a good visibility for the driver according to the information read. Our model is built using stepwise refinement with the Event-B method. We consider all the features of the case study, all proof obligations have been discharged using the rodin provers. Our model has been validated using ProB by applying the different provided scenarios. This validation has permitted us to point out and correct some mistakes, ambiguities and oversights in the first versions of the case study.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/link.springer.com\/content\/pdf\/10.1007%2F978-3-030-48077-6_28.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{mammar2020abz,
title={{An Event-B Model of an Automotive Adaptive Exterior Light System}},
author={Mammar, Amel and Frappier, Marc and Laleau, Regine},
booktitle={7th International Conference on Rigorous State Based Methods (ABZ'20)},
pages={351--366},
year={2020},
organization={Springer}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/method/event-b">Event-B&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:amel.mammar@telecom-sudparis.eu;marc.frappier@usherbrooke.ca;laleau@u-pec.fr">authors&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>An Event-B Model of the Hybrid ERTMS/ETCS Level 3 Standard</title><link>/publication/mammar2018abz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/mammar2018abz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This paper presents an Event-B model of the ABZ2018 case study on the European Rail Traffic Management System (ERTMS) standard. The case study focusses on the management of fixed virtual sub-sections (VSS). We model the hybrid level 3 of the standard, which assumes that trains may be either equipped with an on-board train integrity monitoring system (TIMS) and that they report their position and integrity, ERTMS trains not fitted with TIMS that report only their front position or non-ERTMS trains that do not report any information about their position. We take into account most of the main features of the case study. Our model is decomposed into four refinements. All proof obligations have been discharged using the Rodin provers, except those related to the computation of the VSS state machine, which was found to be ambiguous (nondeterministic). Our model has been validated using ProB. The main safety property, which is that ERTMS trains do not collide, is proved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "https:\/\/www.irit.fr\/ABZ-CS\/html_files\/files\/2018\/PDF\/MFJFL_ABZ2018.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@inproceedings{DBLP:conf/asm/MammarFFL18,
author = {Amel Mammar and
Marc Frappier and
Steve Jeffrey Tueno Fotso and
R{\'{e}}gine Laleau},
title = {An Event-B Model of the Hybrid {ERTMS/ETCS} Level 3 Standard},
booktitle = {Abstract State Machines, Alloy, B, TLA, VDM, and {Z} - 6th International
Conference, {ABZ} 2018, Southampton, UK, June 5-8, 2018, Proceedings},
pages = {353--366},
year = {2018},
crossref = {DBLP:conf/asm/2018}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Model Archive:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/data/abz18/mammar2018abz.zip">ZIP&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/method/event-b">Event-B&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Resources and tools:&lt;/strong>
Rodin, ProB&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Website:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://info.usherbrooke.ca/mfrappier/abz2018-ERTMS-Case-Study" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://info.usherbrooke.ca/mfrappier/abz2018-ERTMS-Case-Study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:amel.mammar@telecom-sudparis.eu;laleau@u-pec.fr">authors&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modeling the Hybrid ERTMS/ETCS Level 3 Standard Using a Formal Requirements Engineering Approach</title><link>/publication/fotso2018abz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/fotso2018abz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This paper presents a specification of the hybrid ERTMS/ETCS level 3 standard in the framework of the case study proposed for the 6th edition of the ABZ conference. The specification is based on the method and tools, developed in the ANR FORMOSE project, for the modeling and formal verification of critical and complex system requirements. The requirements are specified with SysML/KAOS goal diagrams and are automatically translated into B System specifications, in order to obtain the architecture of the formal specification. Domain properties are specified by ontologies with the SysML/KAOS domain modeling language, based on OWL and PLIB. Their automatic translation completes the structural part of the formal specification. The only part of the specification, which must be manually completed, is the body of events. The construction is incremental, based on the refinement mechanisms existing within the involved methods. The formal specification of the case study is composed of seven refinement levels and all the proofs have been discharged with the Rodin prover.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "http:\/\/info.usherbrooke.ca\/mfrappier\/abz2018-ERTMS-Case-Study-Formose\/ABZ2018-_ERTMS_Case_Study.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@InProceedings{10.1007/978-3-319-91271-4_18,
author=&amp;quot;Tueno Fotso, Steve Jeffrey
and Frappier, Marc
and Laleau, R{\'e}gine
and Mammar, Amel&amp;quot;,
editor=&amp;quot;Butler, Michael
and Raschke, Alexander
and Hoang, Thai Son
and Reichl, Klaus&amp;quot;,
title=&amp;quot;Modeling the Hybrid ERTMS/ETCS Level 3 Standard Using a Formal Requirements Engineering Approach&amp;quot;,
booktitle=&amp;quot;Abstract State Machines, Alloy, B, TLA, VDM, and Z&amp;quot;,
year=&amp;quot;2018&amp;quot;,
publisher=&amp;quot;Springer International Publishing&amp;quot;,
address=&amp;quot;Cham&amp;quot;,
pages=&amp;quot;262--276&amp;quot;,
isbn=&amp;quot;978-3-319-91271-4&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Model Archive:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/data/abz18/fotso2018abz.zip">ZIP&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Presentation:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/data/abz18/fotso2018abz.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/method/event-b">Event-B&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="/method/b">B Method&lt;/a>, and SysML/KAOS Requirements Engineering Method&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Resources and tools:&lt;/strong>
Openflexo, Rodin, The SysMLKaos Domain Modeling Tool&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Required OS:&lt;/strong>
Linux, Mac, Windows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Website:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/stuenofotso/SysML_KAOS_Domain_Model_Parser/tree/master/ABZ18_ERTMS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://github.com/stuenofotso/SysML_KAOS_Domain_Model_Parser/tree/master/ABZ18_ERTMS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Remarks and recommendation:&lt;/strong>
The developed model focuses on formal verification of the main requirements of the protocol. Its main objective is to assess the SysML/KAOS method and to compare it with direct specification approaches using only plain Event-B.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Modelling a Hemodialysis Machine Using Algebraic State-Transition Diagrams and B-like Methods</title><link>/publication/fayolle2016abz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/fayolle2016abz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This paper presents the specification of the hemodialysis case study, proposed by ABZ'16 conference. The specification was carried out by a coupling of Algebraic State-Transition Diagrams (ASTD) and B-like methods. astd are a graphical notation, based on automata and process algebra operators. They provide an easy-to-read specification of the dynamic behaviour of the system. The data model is specified using the Event-B language. The system is incrementally designed using extended refinement of both methods.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- ## Document
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "\/fayolle2016abz.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
-->
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@InProceedings{10.1007/978-3-319-33600-8_33,
author=&amp;quot;Fayolle, Thomas
and Frappier, Marc
and Gervais, Fr{\'e}d{\'e}ric
and Laleau, R{\'e}gine&amp;quot;,
editor=&amp;quot;Butler, Michael
and Schewe, Klaus-Dieter
and Mashkoor, Atif
and Biro, Miklos&amp;quot;,
title=&amp;quot;Modelling a Hemodialysis Machine Using Algebraic State-Transition Diagrams and B-like Methods&amp;quot;,
booktitle=&amp;quot;Abstract State Machines, Alloy, B, TLA, VDM, and Z&amp;quot;,
year=&amp;quot;2016&amp;quot;,
publisher=&amp;quot;Springer International Publishing&amp;quot;,
address=&amp;quot;Cham&amp;quot;,
pages=&amp;quot;394--408&amp;quot;,
isbn=&amp;quot;978-3-319-33600-8&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
Algebraic State-Transition Diagrams (ASTD)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:marc.frappier@usherbrooke.ca">authors&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Modeling a landing gear system in Event-B</title><link>/publication/mammar2015sttt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/mammar2015sttt/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This article describes the Event-B modeling of a landing gear system of an aircraft whose complete description can be found in Boniol and Wiels (The Landing Gear System Case Study, ABZ Case Study, Communications in Computer Information Science, vol 433, Springer, Berlin, 2014). This real-life case study has been proposed by the ABZ’2014 track that took place in Toulouse, the European capital of the aeronautic industry. Our modeling is based on the Parnas and Madey’s 4-Variable Model that permits to consider the different parts of a system. These parts are incrementally introduced using the Event-B refinement technique. The entire development has been carried out with the Rodin toolset. To ensure the correctness of the different components, we use several verification techniques (animation, model checking and proof) depending on the complexity and the kind of the properties to verify. Basically, prior to the proof phase that can be tedious and complex, we use the animator ANIMB and the model checker PROB that permit to discover some trivial inconsistencies. Once no error is reported, we start the proof phase by using the Atelier B and SMT provers which we installed on Rodin. We conclude the article by drawing up some key findings of and lessons learned from this experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- ## Document
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "\/mammar2015sttt.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
-->
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@Article{Mammar2017,
author=&amp;quot;Mammar, Amel
and Laleau, R{\'e}gine&amp;quot;,
title=&amp;quot;Modeling a landing gear system in Event-B&amp;quot;,
journal=&amp;quot;International Journal on Software Tools for Technology Transfer&amp;quot;,
year=&amp;quot;2017&amp;quot;,
month=&amp;quot;Apr&amp;quot;,
day=&amp;quot;01&amp;quot;,
volume=&amp;quot;19&amp;quot;,
number=&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;,
pages=&amp;quot;167--186&amp;quot;,
abstract=&amp;quot;This article describes the Event-B modeling of a landing gear system of an aircraft whose complete description can be found in Boniol and Wiels (The Landing Gear System Case Study, ABZ Case Study, Communications in Computer Information Science, vol 433, Springer, Berlin, 2014). This real-life case study has been proposed by the ABZ'2014 track that took place in Toulouse, the European capital of the aeronautic industry. Our modeling is based on the Parnas and Madey's 4-Variable Model that permits to consider the different parts of a system. These parts are incrementally introduced using the Event-B refinement technique. The entire development has been carried out with the Rodin toolset. To ensure the correctness of the different components, we use several verification techniques (animation, model checking and proof) depending on the complexity and the kind of the properties to verify. Basically, prior to the proof phase that can be tedious and complex, we use the animator AnimB and the model checker ProB that permit to discover some trivial inconsistencies. Once no error is reported, we start the proof phase by using the Atelier B and SMT provers which we installed on Rodin. We conclude the article by drawing up some key findings of and lessons learned from this experience.&amp;quot;,
issn=&amp;quot;1433-2787&amp;quot;,
doi=&amp;quot;10.1007/s10009-015-0391-0&amp;quot;,
url=&amp;quot;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10009-015-0391-0&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Model Archive : Not available
Presentation : Not available
Used formal method : Event-B
Resources and tools : Rodin, ProB
Required OS : Linux, Mac, Windows
Website : Not available
Remarks and recommendation : No&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modeling a Landing Gear System in Event-B</title><link>/publication/mammar2014abz/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/mammar2014abz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This paper describes the Event-B modeling of the landing gear system of an aircraft whose the complete description can be found in [3]. This real-life case study has been proposed by the ABZ’2014 track that takes place in Toulouse, the European capital of the aeronautic industry. Our modeling is based on the Parnas and Madey’s 4-Variable Model that permits to consider the different parts of a system. These parts are incremently introduced using the Event-B refinement technique. The entire development has been carried out under the Rodin toolset. To validate and prove the different components, we use the Atelier B, SMT and ML provers which are plugged to Rodin.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="document">Document&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="pdfobject-viewer">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="/js/pdfobject.min.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
var url = "http:\/\/www-public.imtbs-tsp.eu\/~mammar_a\/LandGearsModeling.pdf";
PDFObject.embed( url, "#pdfobject-viewer" );
&lt;/script>
&lt;style>
.pdfobject-container
{
height: 30rem;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>% BibTex
@InProceedings{10.1007/978-3-319-07512-9_6,
author=&amp;quot;Mammar, Amel
and Laleau, R{\'e}gine&amp;quot;,
editor=&amp;quot;Boniol, Fr{\'e}d{\'e}ric
and Wiels, Virginie
and Ait Ameur, Yamine
and Schewe, Klaus-Dieter&amp;quot;,
title=&amp;quot;Modeling a Landing Gear System in Event-B&amp;quot;,
booktitle=&amp;quot;ABZ 2014: The Landing Gear Case Study&amp;quot;,
year=&amp;quot;2014&amp;quot;,
publisher=&amp;quot;Springer International Publishing&amp;quot;,
address=&amp;quot;Cham&amp;quot;,
pages=&amp;quot;80--94&amp;quot;,
abstract=&amp;quot;This paper describes the Event-B modeling of the landing gear system of an aircraft whose the complete description can be found in [3]. This real-life case study has been proposed by the ABZ'2014 track that takes place in Toulouse, the European capital of the aeronautic industry. Our modeling is based on the Parnas and Madey's 4-Variable Model that permits to consider the different parts of a system. These parts are incremently introduced using the Event-B refinement technique. The entire development has been carried out under the Rodin toolset. To validate and prove the different components, we use the Atelier B, SMT and ML provers which are plugged to Rodin.&amp;quot;,
isbn=&amp;quot;978-3-319-07512-9&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="sources">Sources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Used formal method:&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="/method/event-b">Event-B&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Resources and tools:&lt;/strong>
Rodin, ProB&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please contact the &lt;a href ="mailto:amel.mammar@telecom-sudparis.eu;laleau@u-pec.fr">authors&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>